cgispy.com 2019-08-07

# URLSpot.com

URLSpot.com cares about your privacy. For this reason, we collect and use personal data only as it might be needed for us to deliver to you our world-class products, services, websites and mobile applications (collectively, our “Services”). Your personal data includes information such as: 

  * Name
  * Address
  * Telephone number
  * Date of birth
  * Email address
  * Other data collected that could directly or indirectly identify you.

Our Privacy Policy is intended to describe to you how and what data we collect, and how and why we use your personal data. It also describes options we provide for you to access, update or otherwise take control of your personal data that we process. 

If at any time you have questions about our practices or any of your rights described below, you may reach our Data Protection Officer (“DPO”) and our dedicated team that supports this office by contacting us at privacy@secureserver.net. This inbox is actively monitored and managed so that we can deliver an experience that you can confidently trust. 

Likewise, we’ve also created a [Privacy Center](https://help.secureserver.net/article/27875?pl_id=2060) to provide answers to your most common questions, quick links to access your Account Settings, instructions on how to exercise certain rights that might be available to you, and definitions to key terms and concepts noted in this Privacy Policy. 

****Che informazioni raccogliamo?** **

Raccogliamo i dati in modo da poter fornire la migliore esperienza possibile quando si utilizzano i nostri Servizi. Molti di quelli che si ritengono essere dati personali verranno raccolti direttamente dall'Utente quando l'Utente:

  1. crea un account o acquistare uno qualsiasi dei nostri Servizi (es: dati di fatturazione, tra cui nome, indirizzo, numero di carta di credito, documenti ufficiali di identificazione); 
  2. richiede assistenza al nostro pluripremiato team di assistenza clienti (es: numero di telefono); 
  3. completa questo modulo di contatto o richiedi la newsletter o altre informazioni su di noi (ad es: email); o 
  4. partecipa a concorsi e sondaggi, fare domanda per un posto di lavoro o partecipare in altro modo ad attività che promuoviamo e che potrebbero richiedere informazioni sull'Utente.

Tuttavia, raccogliamo anche informazioni aggiuntive quando forniamo i Servizi all'Utente al fine di garantire le prestazioni previste in modo ottimale. Questi metodi di raccolta potrebbero non essere evidenti all'Utente, per questo motivo desideriamo evidenziarli e illustrarli di seguito con maggiore dettaglio, in particolare quali sono (in quanto possono variare col tempo) e come funzionano:

**Informazioni relative all'account** vengono raccolte in associazione con l'utilizzo dei nostri Servizi, come numero di conto, acquisti, quando i prodotti si rinnovano o scadono, richieste di informazioni e richieste al servizio clienti e note o dettagli che spiegano ciò che l'Utente ha richiesto e come noi abbiamo risposto.

**I cookie e tecnologie analoghe** sui nostri siti web e sulle nostre applicazioni mobili ci consentono di monitorare le abitudini di navigazione dell'Utente, i link cliccati, gli articoli acquistati, il tipo di dispositivo e di raccogliere vari dati, tra cui analisi, su come utilizzi e interagisca con i nostri Servizi. Questo ci permette di fornire all'Utente un'offerta di prodotti più rilevanti, una migliore esperienza sui nostri siti e le nostre applicazioni per dispositivi mobili e di raccogliere, analizzare e migliorare le prestazioni dei nostri Servizi. Ci riserviamo inoltre di raccogliere la posizione dell'Utente (indirizzo IP) in modo da poter personalizzare i Servizi offerti. Per ulteriori informazioni e per scoprire come gestire le tecnologie che utilizziamo, leggere la nostra [Politica sui cookie](https://www.secureserver.net/legal/agreements/cookie-policy?prog_id=urlspot&pl_id=2060). 

I **dati sull'utilizzo dei servizi** vengono raccolti automaticamente quando utilizzi nostri servizi e interagisci con essi, compresi i metadati, i file di log, cookie/ID dispositivo, tempo di caricamento della pagina, tempo di risposta del server e informazioni approssimative sulla posizione per misurare le prestazioni del sito web e migliorare i nostri sistemi, compresa l'ottimizzazione della risoluzione del DNS, del routing di rete e delle configurazioni dei server. Nello specifico, vengono raccolti interazioni dell'Utente con le funzioni, i contenuti e i collegamenti (inclusi quelli di terze parti, come i plugin dei social media) contenuti nei Servizi: l'indirizzo IP (Internet Protocol), il tipo e le impostazioni del browser, la data e l'ora di utilizzo dei Servizi, le informazioni sulla configurazione e i plugin del browser, le preferenze linguistiche e i dati dei cookie, le informazioni sui dispositivi che accedono ai Servizi, incluso il tipo di dispositivo, il sistema operativo utilizzato, le impostazioni del dispositivo, gli ID delle applicazioni, gli identificatori unici del dispositivo e i dati sugli errori.

**Dati Integrati** sull'Utente possono essere forniti da altre fonti, compresi database disponibili pubblicamente o da terze parti dalle quali abbiamo acquistato dati, e in questo caso combinare tali dati con gli altri dati già in nostro possesso sull'Utente così da aggiornare, espandere e analizzare i nostri archivi, identificare nuovi clienti e fornire prodotti e servizi che potrebbero essere interessanti per l'Utente. Qualora l'Utente ci fornisca dati personali relativi ad altri soggetti, o se altri ci forniscono dati relativi all'Utente, noi utilizzeremo tali dati solo per gli scopi specifici per i quali ci sono stati forniti.

****How we utilize information.** **

We strongly believe in both minimizing the data we collect and limiting its use and purpose to only that (1) for which we have been given permission, (2) as necessary to deliver the Services you purchase or interact with, or (3) as we might be required or permitted for legal compliance or other lawful purposes. These uses include:

**Delivering, improving, updating and enhancing the Services we provide to you.** We collect various information relating to your purchase, use and/or interactions with our Services. We utilize this information to:

  * Improve and optimize the operation and performance of our Services (again, including our websites and mobile applications) 
  * Diagnose problems with and identify any security risks, errors, or needed enhancements to the Services 
  * Detect and prevent fraud and abuse of our Services and systems 
  * Collecting aggregate statistics about use of the Services 
  * Understand and analyze how you use our Services and what products and services are most relevant to you. 

Often, much of the data collected is aggregated or statistical data about how individuals use our Services, and is not linked to any personal data, but to the extent it is itself personal data, or is linked or linkable to personal data, we treat it accordingly. 

**Sharing with trusted third parties.** We may share your personal data with affiliated companies within our corporate family, with third parties with which we have partnered to allow you to integrate their services into our own Services, and with trusted third party service providers as necessary for them to perform services on our behalf, such as:

  * Processing credit card payments 
  * Serving advertisements 
  * Conducting contests or surveys 
  * Performing analysis of our Services and customers demographics 
  * Communicating with you, such as by way email or survey delivery 
  * Customer relationship management. 

We only share your personal data as necessary for any third party to provide the services as requested or as needed on our behalf. These third parties (and any subcontractors) are subject to strict data processing terms and conditions and are prohibited from utilizing, sharing or retaining your personal data for any purpose other than as they have been specifically contracted for (or without your consent).

We may also share your information with third parties for the purpose of facilitating/allowing a merger, acquisition or sale of all or substantially all of our assets, in which case the acquiring company may continue to utilize your data in the manner for which it was provided and intended.

**Communicating with you.** We may contact you directly or through a third party service provider regarding products or services you have signed up or purchased from us, such as necessary to deliver transactional or service related communications. We may also contact you with offers for additional services we think you’ll find valuable if you give us consent, or where allowed based upon legitimate interests. You don’t need to provide consent as a condition to purchase our goods or services. These contacts may include:

  * Email 
  * Text (SMS) messages 
  * Telephone calls 
  * Automated phone calls or text messages. 

You may also update your subscription preferences with respect to receiving communications from us and/or our partners by signing into your account and visiting “Account Settings” page. 

If we collect information from you in connection with a co-branded offer, it will be clear at the point of collection who is collecting the information and whose privacy policy applies. In addition, it will describe any choice options you have in regards to the use and/or sharing of your personal data with a co-branded partner, as well as how to exercise those options.

If you make use of a service that allows you to import contacts (ex. using email marketing services to send emails on your behalf), we will only use the contacts and any other personal information for the requested service. If you believe that anyone has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at privacy@secureserver.net.

**Transfer of personal data abroad.** If you utilize our Services from a country other than the country where our servers are located, your communications with us may result in transferring your personal data across international borders. Also, when you call us or initiate a chat, we may provide you with support from one of our global locations outside your country of origin. In these cases, your personal data is handled according to this Privacy Policy.

**Compliance with legal, regulatory and law enforcement requests.** We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (such as subpoena requests), to protect our property and rights or the property and rights of a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we consider to be illegal or unethical.

To the extent we are legally permitted to do so, we will take reasonable steps to notify you in the event that we are required to provide your personal information to third parties as part of legal process. We will also share your information to the extent necessary to comply with ICANN or any ccTLD rules, regulations and policies when you register a domain name with us. For reasons critical to maintaining the security, stability and resiliency of the Internet, this includes the transfer of domain name registration information to the underlying domain registry operator and escrow provider, and publication of that information as required by ICANN in the public WHOIS database.

**Website analytics.** We use multiple web analytics tools provided by service partners such as Google Analytics, MixPanel and Singular to collect information about how you interact with our website or mobile applications, including what pages you visit, what site you visited prior to visiting our website, how much time you spend on each page, what operating system and web browser you use and network and IP information. We use the information provided by these tools to improve our Services. These tools place persistent cookies in your browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit our website. Each cookie cannot be used by anyone other than the service provider (ex: Google for Google Analytics). The information collected from the cookie may be transmitted to and stored by these service partners on servers in a country other than the country in which you reside. Though information collected does not include personal data such as name, address, billing information, etc., the information collected is used and shared by these service providers in accordance with their individual privacy policies. You can control the technologies we use by managing your settings through our [Cookie Policy](https://www.secureserver.net/legal/agreements/cookie-policy?prog_id=urlspot&pl_id=2060) or the ‘cookie banners” that may be presented (depending on URL of website visited) when you first visit our webpages, or by utilizing settings in your browser or third-party tools, such as [Disconnect](https://disconnect.me/disconnect), [Ghostery](https://www.ghostery.com/) and others.

**Targeted advertisements.** Targeted ads or interest-based offers may be presented to you based on your activities on our webpages, and other websites, and based on the products you currently own. These offers will display as varying product banners presented to you while browsing. We also partner with third parties to manage our advertising on our webpages and other websites. Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about such activities in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests, and to measure advertising effectiveness. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) [or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)]. Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

**Third-party websites.** Our website and our mobile applications contain links to third-party websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of third-party sites. Please read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

****I privacy Shield Framework. tra EU e USA e tra Svizzera e USA.** **

L'azienda capogruppo, URLSpot.com Operating Company, LLC (e le aziende collegate, incluse URLSpot.com.com, LLC, Blue Razor Domains, LLC, Starfield Technologies, LLC, Domains by Proxy, LLC, Outright, Inc., Mad Mimi, Inc. e Media Temple, Inc.) partecipano a e hanno certificato la loro conformità al Privacy Shield Framework tra EU e USA e tra Svizzera e USA. URLSpot.com Operating Company, LLC si impegna a gestire tutti i dati personali ricevuti dai paesi membri dell'Unione Europea (UE) o dalla Svizzera, come previsto dal Privacy Shield Framework, secondo i Principi applicabili del Framework. Per maggiori informazioni sul Privacy Shield Framework, consultare l'[Elenco Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list) del Dipartimento del Commercio degli USA.

URLSpot.com Operating Company, LLC è responsabile per il trattamento dei dati personali ricevuti, in base a quanto stabilito dal Privacy Shield Framework, che successivamente trasferisce a una terza parte che agisce in qualità di agente per suo conto. URLSpot.com Operating Company, LLC opera conformemente ai Principi del Privacy Shield per gli ulteriori trasferimenti di dati personali provenienti dall'Unione Europea e dalla Svizzera, comprese le disposizioni sulla responsabilità per i trasferimenti successivi.

Per quanto riguarda i dati personali ricevuti o trasferiti ai sensi del Privacy Shield Framework, URLSpot.com Operating Company, LLC è soggetta alla regolamentazione della Federal Trade Commission degli USA. In determinate situazioni, a URLSpot.com Operating Company LLC può venire chiesto di divulgare dati personali in risposta a richieste delle pubbliche autorità, comprese le richieste relative alla sicurezza nazionale o delle forze dell'ordine.

Se l'Utente è preoccupato per un determinato utilizzo dei dati o per questioni relative la privacy che non sono state chiaramente illustrate, invitiamo a contattare l'ente terzo incaricato di risolvere tali controversie (gratis) all'indirizzo <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. In determinate condizioni, descritte in maggior dettaglio nel [sito web del Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/), l'Utente può richiedere un arbitrato vincolante qualora siano esaurite le altre procedure per la risoluzione delle controversie.

In conformità ai Principi del Privacy Shield, URLSpot.com Operating Company, LLC si impegna a risolvere eventuali reclami sulla nostra raccolta o utilizzo delle informazioni personali degli utenti. Per domande o reclami riguardanti la nostra politica sul Privacy Shield, gli individui appartenenti alla Comunità Europea e alla Svizzera sono tenuti innanzitutto a contattarci tramite qualsiasi modalità indicata nella sezione "CONTATTACI" inclusa di seguito nella presente Politica sulla privacy. 

URLSpot.com Operating Company, LLC ha inoltre dichiarato il suo impegno a cooperare con il comitato istituito dai Garanti per la protezione dei dati personali dell'UE e dallo Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner in merito a reclami sul Privacy Shield non risolti e relativi ai dati sulle risorse umane trasferiti dall'UE e dalla Svizzera nel contesto dei rapporti di lavoro.

****Come l'Utente può accedere, aggiornare o eliminare i propri dati.** **

Per accedere, visualizzare, aggiornare, eliminare o trasferire facilmente i propri dati personali (quando disponibili), o per aggiornare le preferenze di abbonamento, l'Utente deve accedere al suo Account e andare a Impostazioni dell'account." Consultare il nostro [Centro sulla privacy](https://help.secureserver.net/article/27875?pl_id=2060) per ulteriori informazioni e indicazioni sull'accesso, l'aggiornamento o la cancellazione dei dati. 

Se l'Utente effettua una richiesta per eliminare i suoi dati personali e tali dati sono necessari per i prodotti o i Servizi acquistati dall'Utente, la richiesta verrà soddisfatta solamente se tali dati non sono più necessari per i Servizi acquistati o non sono più richiesti per i nostri obiettivi commerciali legittimi o per soddisfare requisiti legali o contrattuali in materia di conservazione dei dati.

Se per qualsiasi motivo l'Utente non è in grado di accedere alle Impostazioni dell'account o al nostro Centro sulla privacy, può anche contattarci tramite uno dei metodi descritti nella sezione "Contattaci" di seguito. 

****How we secure, store and retain your data.** **

We follow generally accepted standards to store and protect the personal data we collect, both during transmission and once received and stored, including utilization of encryption where appropriate.

We retain personal data only for as long as necessary to provide the Services you have requested and thereafter for a variety of legitimate legal or business purposes. These might include retention periods:

  * mandated by law, contract or similar obligations applicable to our business operations; 
  * for preserving, resolving, defending or enforcing our legal/contractual rights; or 
  * needed to maintain adequate and accurate business and financial records.

If you have any questions about the security or retention of your personal data, you can contact us at privacy@secureserver.net.

****Notifiche _'Do Not Track'_.** **

Alcuni browser consentono all'Utente di notificare ai siti web visitati di non effettuare il tracciamento dell'Utente utilizzando un segnale "Do Not Track". Non vi è alcun accordo tra chi opera nel settore su ciò che un segnale "Do Not Track" significhi in questo contesto. Così come tanti altri siti web e servizi online, al momento non modifichiamo le nostre procedure quando riceviamo un segnale "Do Not Track" dal browser di un visitatore. Per maggiori informazioni sui segnali "Do Not Track" è possibile visitare il sito [www.allaboutdnt.com](https://allaboutdnt.com/).

****Limitazioni relative all'età.** **

I nostri servizi possono essere acquistati solo per persone di età superiore ai 18 anni. I nostri Servizi non sono rivolti o destinati ad un pubblico di età inferiore ai 18 anni. Se l'Utente è a conoscenza o ha motivo di ritenere che qualcuno che abbia meno di 18 anni ci abbia fornito dati personali lo invitiamo a contattarci.

****Modifiche alla nostra Politica sulla privacy.** **

Ci riserviamo il diritto di modificare la presente Politica sulla privacy in qualsiasi momento. Qualora decida di modificare la Politica sulla privacy, pubblicheremo tali modifiche nella Politica sulla privacy e in qualunque punto ritenga opportuno, affinché l'Utente sia informato in merito ai dati raccolti, alle relative modalità di utilizzo e alle circostanze nelle quali vengono divulgate, se del caso. Eventuali modifiche sostanziali alla presente Politica sulla privacy saranno rese note agli utenti nel presente documento, tramite email o mediante una notifica sulla home page almeno trenta (30) giorni prima dell'implementazione delle modifiche.

****Autorità per la protezione dei dati.** **

Chi risiede nell'Area Economica Europea (EEA) e ritiene che i suoi dati personali siano soggetti al Regolamento generale sulla protezione dei dati (GDPR) può rivolgere eventuali domande o reclami alla nostra principale autorità di supervisione o all'autorità di supervisione locale, l'Information Commissioner's Office del Regno Unito, secondo quanto espresso di seguito:

Information Commissioner's Office

Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF, Regno Unito

Telefono: 0303 123 1113

****Contattaci.** **

Per domande in materia di privacy, dubbi o reclami sulla nostra Politica sulla privacy, sulle nostre pratiche o i nostri Servizi, è possibile contattare l'ufficio del Data Protection Officer via email all'indirizzo privacy@URLSpot.com.com. In alternativa, l'Utente può contattarci in uno dei seguenti modi:

  * _Per posta ordinaria_ : Attn: Office of the Data Protection Officer, 14455 North Hayden Road, Suite 219, Scottsdale, AZ 85260 USA o per i clienti con sede nell'Area Economica Europea, Attn: Legal, Office of the DPO, 5th Floor, The Shipping Building, Old Vinyl Factory, 252-254 Blyth Road, Hayes, UB3 1HA.  

  * _Per telefono_ : 043 508 3959. 

**_Risponderemo a tutte le richieste, le domande o i dubbi entro trenta (30) giorni._**

Revisione: 04.04.2019  
Copyright © 2000-2019 URLSpot.com.com, LLC Tutti i diritti riservati.

****Contact us.** **

If you have any privacy-related questions, concerns or complaints about our Privacy Policy, our practices or our Services, you may contact our Office of the DPO by email at privacy@secureserver.net. In the alternative, you may contact us by either of the following means:

  * _By Mail_ : Attn: Office of the Data Protection Officer, 14455 North Hayden Road, Suite 219, Scottsdale, AZ 85260 USA, or for customers established in the EEA, Attn: Legal, Office of the DPO, 5th Floor, The Shipping Building, Old Vinyl Factory, 252-254 Blyth Road, Hayes, UB3 1HA.  

  * _By Phone_ : 043 508 3959. 

**_We will respond to all requests, inquiries or concerns within thirty (30) days._**

Revised: 04.04.2019  
Copyright © 2000-2019 URLSpot.com.com, LLC All Rights Reserved.
